<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://fong-lab.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://fong-lab.github.io/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2025-03-11T16:32:44+00:00</updated><id>https://fong-lab.github.io/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Fong Lab</title><subtitle>Harnessing plasticity for neural rehabilitation and lifelong learning</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Welcome Max :)</title><link href="https://fong-lab.github.io/2025/02/04/welcome-max.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Welcome Max :)" /><published>2025-02-04T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-03-11T16:30:56+00:00</updated><id>https://fong-lab.github.io/2025/02/04/welcome-max</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://fong-lab.github.io/2025/02/04/welcome-max.html"><![CDATA[<p>We are delighted to welcome Xinyuan (Max) Cao to the Fong Lab for a research rotation. Max is a PhD student in Neuroscience at Emory University who is broadly interested in sensory and social neuroscience.  He joins the lab with research experience using machine learning to undercover hormonal interactions in the brains of monogamous rodents. During his rotation, he will be investigating how varied patterns of stimulation in the mouse lateral geniculate nucleus impact physiology in thalamocortical and intracortical circuits.  Welcome, Max!</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[We are delighted to welcome Xinyuan (Max) Cao to the Fong Lab for a research rotation. Max is a PhD student in Neuroscience at Emory University who is broadly interested in sensory and social neuroscience. He joins the lab with research experience using machine learning to undercover hormonal interactions in the brains of monogamous rodents. During his rotation, he will be investigating how varied patterns of stimulation in the mouse lateral geniculate nucleus impact physiology in thalamocortical and intracortical circuits. Welcome, Max!]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://fong-lab.github.io/images/headshots/cao.png" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://fong-lab.github.io/images/headshots/cao.png" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Welcome Kenadie :)</title><link href="https://fong-lab.github.io/2025/01/13/welcome-kenadie.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Welcome Kenadie :)" /><published>2025-01-13T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-03-11T16:30:56+00:00</updated><id>https://fong-lab.github.io/2025/01/13/welcome-kenadie</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://fong-lab.github.io/2025/01/13/welcome-kenadie.html"><![CDATA[<p>Kenadie Smith has joined our lab!  Kenadie is a junior at Charles R. Drew Charter School, and a high school research scholar in the ENGAGES Program at Georgia Tech working under the mentorship of graduate student, Yichao Zhao.  She has a strong passion for mechanical engineering and design, and we’re excited to do some science together!  Welcome, Kenadie!</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Kenadie Smith has joined our lab! Kenadie is a junior at Charles R. Drew Charter School, and a high school research scholar in the ENGAGES Program at Georgia Tech working under the mentorship of graduate student, Yichao Zhao. She has a strong passion for mechanical engineering and design, and we’re excited to do some science together! Welcome, Kenadie!]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://fong-lab.github.io/images/headshots/smith.png" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://fong-lab.github.io/images/headshots/smith.png" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Welcome Ruhi :)</title><link href="https://fong-lab.github.io/2025/01/06/welcome-ruhi.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Welcome Ruhi :)" /><published>2025-01-06T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-03-11T16:30:56+00:00</updated><id>https://fong-lab.github.io/2025/01/06/welcome-ruhi</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://fong-lab.github.io/2025/01/06/welcome-ruhi.html"><![CDATA[<p>We are happy to welcome Ruhi Dua to the Fong Lab.  Ruhi is an undergraduate student majoring in Biomedical Engineering and minoring in Computing &amp; Intelligence, working with graduate student, Morgan Bade, on collection and analysis of visual neurophysiology data.  Beyond her research in the lab, Ruhi interested is the application of bioinformatics to neurological disease, drug development, and advancing healthcare practices.  Welcome, Ruhi!</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[We are happy to welcome Ruhi Dua to the Fong Lab. Ruhi is an undergraduate student majoring in Biomedical Engineering and minoring in Computing &amp; Intelligence, working with graduate student, Morgan Bade, on collection and analysis of visual neurophysiology data. Beyond her research in the lab, Ruhi interested is the application of bioinformatics to neurological disease, drug development, and advancing healthcare practices. Welcome, Ruhi!]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://fong-lab.github.io/images/headshots/dua.png" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://fong-lab.github.io/images/headshots/dua.png" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Ming wins NSF CAREER Award</title><link href="https://fong-lab.github.io/2024/09/01/nsf-career-award.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Ming wins NSF CAREER Award" /><published>2024-09-01T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-03-11T16:30:56+00:00</updated><id>https://fong-lab.github.io/2024/09/01/nsf-career-award</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://fong-lab.github.io/2024/09/01/nsf-career-award.html"><![CDATA[<p>Ming has received the NSF CAREER Award in recognition of her work as a scholar-educator.  The grant will support research on rejuvenation of plasticity in the mature brain and educational outreach in the Atlanta-area blind and visually-impaired community.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Ming has received the NSF CAREER Award in recognition of her work as a scholar-educator. The grant will support research on rejuvenation of plasticity in the mature brain and educational outreach in the Atlanta-area blind and visually-impaired community.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://fong-lab.github.io/images/logos/NSF-CAREER-logo.png" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://fong-lab.github.io/images/logos/NSF-CAREER-logo.png" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Welcome Trinity :)</title><link href="https://fong-lab.github.io/2024/08/16/welcome-trinity.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Welcome Trinity :)" /><published>2024-08-16T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-03-11T16:30:56+00:00</updated><id>https://fong-lab.github.io/2024/08/16/welcome-trinity</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://fong-lab.github.io/2024/08/16/welcome-trinity.html"><![CDATA[<p>Today was Match Day at Cristo Rey Atlanta, and we are thrilled that high school senior, Trinity Calvin, matched with our group!  Trinity is an aspiring engineer and president of her school robotics club.  We’re excited for her to join our team and advances our efforts in mechanical design and community outreach. Welcome, Trinity!</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today was Match Day at Cristo Rey Atlanta, and we are thrilled that high school senior, Trinity Calvin, matched with our group! Trinity is an aspiring engineer and president of her school robotics club. We’re excited for her to join our team and advances our efforts in mechanical design and community outreach. Welcome, Trinity!]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://fong-lab.github.io/images/headshots/calvin.png" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://fong-lab.github.io/images/headshots/calvin.png" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Welcome Morgan :)</title><link href="https://fong-lab.github.io/2024/07/15/welcome-morgan.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Welcome Morgan :)" /><published>2024-07-15T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-03-11T16:30:56+00:00</updated><id>https://fong-lab.github.io/2024/07/15/welcome-morgan</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://fong-lab.github.io/2024/07/15/welcome-morgan.html"><![CDATA[<p>We’re excited to welcome Morgan Bade for a graduate research rotation! Morgan is an MD/PhD student at Emory, and starting her PhD training this year.  She is passionate about vision research (woot woot!) and will join us for upcoming month and a half to investigate homeostatic plasticity in the ON visual pathway.  We’re excited to see what she discovers!  Welcome, Morgan!</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[We’re excited to welcome Morgan Bade for a graduate research rotation! Morgan is an MD/PhD student at Emory, and starting her PhD training this year. She is passionate about vision research (woot woot!) and will join us for upcoming month and a half to investigate homeostatic plasticity in the ON visual pathway. We’re excited to see what she discovers! Welcome, Morgan!]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://fong-lab.github.io/images/headshots/bade.png" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://fong-lab.github.io/images/headshots/bade.png" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Welcome Peyton :)</title><link href="https://fong-lab.github.io/2024/06/17/welcome-peyton.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Welcome Peyton :)" /><published>2024-06-17T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-03-11T16:30:56+00:00</updated><id>https://fong-lab.github.io/2024/06/17/welcome-peyton</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://fong-lab.github.io/2024/06/17/welcome-peyton.html"><![CDATA[<p>Peyton-Zoe Jackson has joined our lab as a high school research scholar via the ENGAGES Program at Georgia Tech.  Peyton is a rising senior at Benjamin E. Mays High School with an interest in medicine and engineering.  She will be working with her graduate mentor, Yichao Zhao, to develop optogenetic approaches for driving thalamocortical plasticity.  Welcome, Peyton!</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Peyton-Zoe Jackson has joined our lab as a high school research scholar via the ENGAGES Program at Georgia Tech. Peyton is a rising senior at Benjamin E. Mays High School with an interest in medicine and engineering. She will be working with her graduate mentor, Yichao Zhao, to develop optogenetic approaches for driving thalamocortical plasticity. Welcome, Peyton!]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://fong-lab.github.io/images/headshots/jackson.png" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://fong-lab.github.io/images/headshots/jackson.png" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Goalball tournament</title><link href="https://fong-lab.github.io/2024/05/24/goalball.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Goalball tournament" /><published>2024-05-24T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-03-11T16:30:56+00:00</updated><id>https://fong-lab.github.io/2024/05/24/goalball</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://fong-lab.github.io/2024/05/24/goalball.html"><![CDATA[<p>We love goalball!  The lab returned for a second year to volunteer at the Southeast Regional National Qualifier goalball tournament.  Danielle, Rob, Chao, Nahreen, and Ming helped set up the nets and tape lines and serve as judges/scorekeepers.  We reconnected with friends from last year and met some new ones.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[We love goalball! The lab returned for a second year to volunteer at the Southeast Regional National Qualifier goalball tournament. Danielle, Rob, Chao, Nahreen, and Ming helped set up the nets and tape lines and serve as judges/scorekeepers. We reconnected with friends from last year and met some new ones.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://fong-lab.github.io/images/news/2024-goalball.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://fong-lab.github.io/images/news/2024-goalball.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Chao awarded Wells Fellowship</title><link href="https://fong-lab.github.io/2024/05/20/chao-wells-fellowship.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Chao awarded Wells Fellowship" /><published>2024-05-20T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-03-11T16:30:56+00:00</updated><id>https://fong-lab.github.io/2024/05/20/chao-wells-fellowship</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://fong-lab.github.io/2024/05/20/chao-wells-fellowship.html"><![CDATA[<p>Hooray!  Yichao Zhao has received the J. Norman &amp; Rosalyn Wells Fellowship.  The award will support his work on developing an optogenetic stimulation system for driving plasticity in the mature mouse brain.  Congratulations, Chao!</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Hooray! Yichao Zhao has received the J. Norman &amp; Rosalyn Wells Fellowship. The award will support his work on developing an optogenetic stimulation system for driving plasticity in the mature mouse brain. Congratulations, Chao!]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://fong-lab.github.io/images/headshots/zhao.png" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://fong-lab.github.io/images/headshots/zhao.png" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Robotics workshop for visually-impaired youth</title><link href="https://fong-lab.github.io/2024/04/13/solar-car-workshop.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Robotics workshop for visually-impaired youth" /><published>2024-04-13T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-03-11T16:30:56+00:00</updated><id>https://fong-lab.github.io/2024/04/13/solar-car-workshop</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://fong-lab.github.io/2024/04/13/solar-car-workshop.html"><![CDATA[<p>The Fong lab organized a robotics workshop for blind and visually-impaired youth to build, modify, and race solar cars!  The idea was the brainchild of high school student, Nahreen Shamon Ayala.  Nahreen, Chao, Rob, Rohan, and Ming all participated as mentors.  The workshop took place at Clough Commons and was sponsored by the GT-Emory Department of Biomedical Engineering, the GT Center for Education Integrating Science, Mathematics, and Computing, and the Atlanta Center for Visually Impaired.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Fong lab organized a robotics workshop for blind and visually-impaired youth to build, modify, and race solar cars! The idea was the brainchild of high school student, Nahreen Shamon Ayala. Nahreen, Chao, Rob, Rohan, and Ming all participated as mentors. The workshop took place at Clough Commons and was sponsored by the GT-Emory Department of Biomedical Engineering, the GT Center for Education Integrating Science, Mathematics, and Computing, and the Atlanta Center for Visually Impaired.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://fong-lab.github.io/images/news/2024-solar-car-workshop.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://fong-lab.github.io/images/news/2024-solar-car-workshop.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry></feed>