<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://fong-lab.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://fong-lab.github.io/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2024-06-14T19:53:04+00:00</updated><id>https://fong-lab.github.io/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Fong Lab</title><subtitle>Harnessing plasticity for neural rehabilitation and lifelong learning</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Lab returns goalball tournament</title><link href="https://fong-lab.github.io/2024/05/24/goalball.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Lab returns goalball tournament" /><published>2024-05-24T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-06-14T19:51:59+00:00</updated><id>https://fong-lab.github.io/2024/05/24/goalball</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://fong-lab.github.io/2024/05/24/goalball.html"><![CDATA[<p>We love goalball!  The lab returned for a second year to volunteer at the Southeast Regional National Qualifier goalball tournament.  Danielle, Rob, Chao, Nahreen, and Ming helped set up the nets and tape lines and serve as judges/scorekeepers.  We reconnected with friends from last year and met some new ones.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[We love goalball! The lab returned for a second year to volunteer at the Southeast Regional National Qualifier goalball tournament. Danielle, Rob, Chao, Nahreen, and Ming helped set up the nets and tape lines and serve as judges/scorekeepers. We reconnected with friends from last year and met some new ones.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://fong-lab.github.io/images/news/2024-goalball.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://fong-lab.github.io/images/news/2024-goalball.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Chao awarded Wells Fellowship</title><link href="https://fong-lab.github.io/2024/05/20/chao-wells-fellowship.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Chao awarded Wells Fellowship" /><published>2024-05-20T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-06-14T19:51:59+00:00</updated><id>https://fong-lab.github.io/2024/05/20/chao-wells-fellowship</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://fong-lab.github.io/2024/05/20/chao-wells-fellowship.html"><![CDATA[<p>Hooray!  Yichao Zhao has received the J. Norman &amp; Rosalyn Wells Fellowship.  The award will support his work on developing an optogenetic stimulation system for driving plasticity in the mature mouse brain.  Congratulations, Chao!</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Hooray! Yichao Zhao has received the J. Norman &amp; Rosalyn Wells Fellowship. The award will support his work on developing an optogenetic stimulation system for driving plasticity in the mature mouse brain. Congratulations, Chao!]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://fong-lab.github.io/images/headshots/zhao.png" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://fong-lab.github.io/images/headshots/zhao.png" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Robotics workshop for visually-impaired youth</title><link href="https://fong-lab.github.io/2024/04/13/solar-car-workshop.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Robotics workshop for visually-impaired youth" /><published>2024-04-13T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-06-14T19:51:59+00:00</updated><id>https://fong-lab.github.io/2024/04/13/solar-car-workshop</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://fong-lab.github.io/2024/04/13/solar-car-workshop.html"><![CDATA[<p>The Fong lab organized a robotics workshop for blind and visually-impaired youth to build, modify, and race solar cars!  The idea was the brainchild of high school student, Nahreen Shamon Ayala.  Nahreen, Chao, Rob, Rohan, and Ming all participated as mentors.  The workshop took place at Clough Commons and was sponsored by the GT-Emory Department of Biomedical Engineering, the GT Center for Education Integrating Science, Mathematics, and Computing, and the Atlanta Center for Visually Impaired.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Fong lab organized a robotics workshop for blind and visually-impaired youth to build, modify, and race solar cars! The idea was the brainchild of high school student, Nahreen Shamon Ayala. Nahreen, Chao, Rob, Rohan, and Ming all participated as mentors. The workshop took place at Clough Commons and was sponsored by the GT-Emory Department of Biomedical Engineering, the GT Center for Education Integrating Science, Mathematics, and Computing, and the Atlanta Center for Visually Impaired.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://fong-lab.github.io/images/news/2024-solar-car-workshop.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://fong-lab.github.io/images/news/2024-solar-car-workshop.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Welcome Adam :)</title><link href="https://fong-lab.github.io/2024/03/04/welcome-adam.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Welcome Adam :)" /><published>2024-03-04T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-06-14T19:51:59+00:00</updated><id>https://fong-lab.github.io/2024/03/04/welcome-adam</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://fong-lab.github.io/2024/03/04/welcome-adam.html"><![CDATA[<p>We’re excited to welcome Adam Kotar to the lab as a new research technician.  Adam joins the lab with an MS in Biomedical Engineering from University of Alabama at Birmingham and a BS in Civil Engineering from the University of South Alabama.  He has worked in breast cancer research in recent years, but we’ve successfully wooed him to join our efforts on neural plasticity.  Welcome, Adam!</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[We’re excited to welcome Adam Kotar to the lab as a new research technician. Adam joins the lab with an MS in Biomedical Engineering from University of Alabama at Birmingham and a BS in Civil Engineering from the University of South Alabama. He has worked in breast cancer research in recent years, but we’ve successfully wooed him to join our efforts on neural plasticity. Welcome, Adam!]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://fong-lab.github.io/images/headshots/kotar.png" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://fong-lab.github.io/images/headshots/kotar.png" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Rob presents at SfN</title><link href="https://fong-lab.github.io/2023/11/14/rob-presents-sfn.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Rob presents at SfN" /><published>2023-11-14T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-06-14T19:51:59+00:00</updated><id>https://fong-lab.github.io/2023/11/14/rob-presents-sfn</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://fong-lab.github.io/2023/11/14/rob-presents-sfn.html"><![CDATA[<p>Rob and Chao present a poster at the Society for Neuroscience Meeting in Washington, DC.  It is the first abstract from our lab!</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Rob and Chao present a poster at the Society for Neuroscience Meeting in Washington, DC. It is the first abstract from our lab!]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://fong-lab.github.io/images/news/2023-rob-sfn.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://fong-lab.github.io/images/news/2023-rob-sfn.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Award from Research to Prevent Blindness</title><link href="https://fong-lab.github.io/2023/07/01/RPB-disney-award.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Award from Research to Prevent Blindness" /><published>2023-07-01T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-06-14T19:51:59+00:00</updated><id>https://fong-lab.github.io/2023/07/01/RPB-disney-award</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://fong-lab.github.io/2023/07/01/RPB-disney-award.html"><![CDATA[<p>Woot woot!  We have received the Disney Award for Amblyopia Research from the Research to Prevent Blindness Foundation.  The award will support new work in the lab on retinal cell types that mediate recovery from amblyopia.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Woot woot! We have received the Disney Award for Amblyopia Research from the Research to Prevent Blindness Foundation. The award will support new work in the lab on retinal cell types that mediate recovery from amblyopia.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://fong-lab.github.io/images/logos/RPB-logo.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://fong-lab.github.io/images/logos/RPB-logo.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Welcome Cooper :)</title><link href="https://fong-lab.github.io/2023/06/14/welcome-cooper.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Welcome Cooper :)" /><published>2023-06-14T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-06-14T19:51:59+00:00</updated><id>https://fong-lab.github.io/2023/06/14/welcome-cooper</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://fong-lab.github.io/2023/06/14/welcome-cooper.html"><![CDATA[<p>Cooper Allen has joined out lab this summer to help refine our head restraint devices and building instrumentation to support experimental projects in the lab.  Cooper is an undergraduate at Georgia Tech who joins us from the Department of Mechanical Engineering.  Welcome, Cooper!</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Cooper Allen has joined out lab this summer to help refine our head restraint devices and building instrumentation to support experimental projects in the lab. Cooper is an undergraduate at Georgia Tech who joins us from the Department of Mechanical Engineering. Welcome, Cooper!]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://fong-lab.github.io/images/headshots/allen.png" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://fong-lab.github.io/images/headshots/allen.png" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Lab volunteers at CVI Youth Camp</title><link href="https://fong-lab.github.io/2023/06/13/cvi-camp.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Lab volunteers at CVI Youth Camp" /><published>2023-06-13T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-06-14T19:51:59+00:00</updated><id>https://fong-lab.github.io/2023/06/13/cvi-camp</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://fong-lab.github.io/2023/06/13/cvi-camp.html"><![CDATA[<p>Rohan, Chao, Danielle, Rob, Nahreen, and Ming volunteered with at the Center for Visually Impaired (CVI) youth summer camp.  On the first day, we went grocery shopping and cooked with campers, followed by an afternoon of playing STEM games.  One the second day, we visited the High Museum of Art and made jewelry.  We had a great time getting to know the campers and look forward to an ongoing partnerships with CVI!</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Rohan, Chao, Danielle, Rob, Nahreen, and Ming volunteered with at the Center for Visually Impaired (CVI) youth summer camp. On the first day, we went grocery shopping and cooked with campers, followed by an afternoon of playing STEM games. One the second day, we visited the High Museum of Art and made jewelry. We had a great time getting to know the campers and look forward to an ongoing partnerships with CVI!]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://fong-lab.github.io/images/news/2023-cvi-summer-camp.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://fong-lab.github.io/images/news/2023-cvi-summer-camp.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Welcome Nahreen :)</title><link href="https://fong-lab.github.io/2023/06/06/welcome-nahreen.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Welcome Nahreen :)" /><published>2023-06-06T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-06-14T19:51:59+00:00</updated><id>https://fong-lab.github.io/2023/06/06/welcome-nahreen</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://fong-lab.github.io/2023/06/06/welcome-nahreen.html"><![CDATA[<p>Nahreen Shamon Ayala has joined our lab as a summer scholar.  Nahreen is a student at Cristo Rey Jesuit High School who matched with our lab via the Emory Next Gen Scholars Internship Program.  She will be working on repair and maintenance of Perkins Braillers as part of our partnership with the Center for Visually Impaired.  Welcome, Nahreen!</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Nahreen Shamon Ayala has joined our lab as a summer scholar. Nahreen is a student at Cristo Rey Jesuit High School who matched with our lab via the Emory Next Gen Scholars Internship Program. She will be working on repair and maintenance of Perkins Braillers as part of our partnership with the Center for Visually Impaired. Welcome, Nahreen!]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://fong-lab.github.io/images/headshots/shamon-ayala.png" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://fong-lab.github.io/images/headshots/shamon-ayala.png" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Lab volunteers at goalball tournament</title><link href="https://fong-lab.github.io/2023/06/02/goalball.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Lab volunteers at goalball tournament" /><published>2023-06-02T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-06-14T19:51:59+00:00</updated><id>https://fong-lab.github.io/2023/06/02/goalball</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://fong-lab.github.io/2023/06/02/goalball.html"><![CDATA[<p>Anu, Rohan, Danielle, Rob, and Ming volunteered with Georgia Blind Sports at the 2023 Southeast Regional National Qualifier goalball tournament.  We helped set up the gyms, served as judges/scorekeepers during the tournament, and met lots of amazing people within the greater blind and visually impaired community.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Anu, Rohan, Danielle, Rob, and Ming volunteered with Georgia Blind Sports at the 2023 Southeast Regional National Qualifier goalball tournament. We helped set up the gyms, served as judges/scorekeepers during the tournament, and met lots of amazing people within the greater blind and visually impaired community.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://fong-lab.github.io/images/news/2023-goalball.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://fong-lab.github.io/images/news/2023-goalball.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry></feed>