<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://fong-lab.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://fong-lab.github.io/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2025-05-29T22:43:50+00:00</updated><id>https://fong-lab.github.io/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Fong Lab</title><subtitle>Harnessing plasticity for neural rehabilitation and lifelong learning</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Fong Lab students lead visual illusions demo at Atlanta Science Festival</title><link href="https://fong-lab.github.io/2025/03/08/atlanta-science-festival.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Fong Lab students lead visual illusions demo at Atlanta Science Festival" /><published>2025-03-08T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-05-29T22:42:30+00:00</updated><id>https://fong-lab.github.io/2025/03/08/atlanta-science-festival</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://fong-lab.github.io/2025/03/08/atlanta-science-festival.html"><![CDATA[<p>Nahreen Shamon Ayala and Trinity Calvin gave a demonstration on visual illusions at Atlanta Science Festival!  They used the illusions to teach neuroscience and engineering concepts to children and their families, and distributed goodies for attendees to bring home.  We are proud to have them representing the Fong lab and using vision science to teach/promote STEM in our community.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Nahreen Shamon Ayala and Trinity Calvin gave a demonstration on visual illusions at Atlanta Science Festival! They used the illusions to teach neuroscience and engineering concepts to children and their families, and distributed goodies for attendees to bring home. We are proud to have them representing the Fong lab and using vision science to teach/promote STEM in our community.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://fong-lab.github.io/images/news/2025-trinity-ATL-science-fest.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://fong-lab.github.io/images/news/2025-trinity-ATL-science-fest.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Nahreen awarded Hancock Award</title><link href="https://fong-lab.github.io/2025/02/15/nahreen-hancock-award.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Nahreen awarded Hancock Award" /><published>2025-02-15T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-05-29T22:42:30+00:00</updated><id>https://fong-lab.github.io/2025/02/15/nahreen-hancock-award</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://fong-lab.github.io/2025/02/15/nahreen-hancock-award.html"><![CDATA[<p>Good news alert!  Nahreen Shamon Ayala has received the Charles I. Hancock Endowed Research Fund Award in support of her research proposal on exploring visually-guided locomotion in mice and how these behaviors as altered by neurovisual impairment.  Congratulations, Nahreen!</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Good news alert! Nahreen Shamon Ayala has received the Charles I. Hancock Endowed Research Fund Award in support of her research proposal on exploring visually-guided locomotion in mice and how these behaviors as altered by neurovisual impairment. Congratulations, Nahreen!]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://fong-lab.github.io/images/headshots/shamon-ayala.png" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://fong-lab.github.io/images/headshots/shamon-ayala.png" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Welcome Izzy :)</title><link href="https://fong-lab.github.io/2025/02/04/welcome-izzy.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Welcome Izzy :)" /><published>2025-02-04T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-05-29T22:42:30+00:00</updated><id>https://fong-lab.github.io/2025/02/04/welcome-izzy</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://fong-lab.github.io/2025/02/04/welcome-izzy.html"><![CDATA[<p>We are excited to welcome Isabelle Witteven-Patel to the Fong Lab for a research rotation.  Izzy is a first-year PhD student in the Neuroscience Program at Emory University.  She is interested in cellular physiology in the context of sensory plasticity, and comes to the lab with expertise using electrophysiology to study in cellular and circuit properties in the visual and auditory systems. During her rotation, she will be investigating how ocular dominance plasticity impacts the ON and OFF visual pathways.  Welcome, Izzy!</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[We are excited to welcome Isabelle Witteven-Patel to the Fong Lab for a research rotation. Izzy is a first-year PhD student in the Neuroscience Program at Emory University. She is interested in cellular physiology in the context of sensory plasticity, and comes to the lab with expertise using electrophysiology to study in cellular and circuit properties in the visual and auditory systems. During her rotation, she will be investigating how ocular dominance plasticity impacts the ON and OFF visual pathways. Welcome, Izzy!]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://fong-lab.github.io/images/headshots/witteveen-patel.png" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://fong-lab.github.io/images/headshots/witteveen-patel.png" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Welcome Max :)</title><link href="https://fong-lab.github.io/2025/02/04/welcome-max.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Welcome Max :)" /><published>2025-02-04T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-05-29T22:42:30+00:00</updated><id>https://fong-lab.github.io/2025/02/04/welcome-max</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://fong-lab.github.io/2025/02/04/welcome-max.html"><![CDATA[<p>We are delighted to welcome Xinyuan (Max) Cao to the Fong Lab for a research rotation. Max is a PhD student in Neuroscience at Emory University who is broadly interested in sensory and social neuroscience.  He joins the lab with research experience using machine learning to undercover hormonal interactions in the brains of monogamous rodents. During his rotation, he will be investigating how varied patterns of stimulation in the mouse lateral geniculate nucleus impact physiology in thalamocortical and intracortical circuits.  Welcome, Max!</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[We are delighted to welcome Xinyuan (Max) Cao to the Fong Lab for a research rotation. Max is a PhD student in Neuroscience at Emory University who is broadly interested in sensory and social neuroscience. He joins the lab with research experience using machine learning to undercover hormonal interactions in the brains of monogamous rodents. During his rotation, he will be investigating how varied patterns of stimulation in the mouse lateral geniculate nucleus impact physiology in thalamocortical and intracortical circuits. Welcome, Max!]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://fong-lab.github.io/images/headshots/cao.png" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://fong-lab.github.io/images/headshots/cao.png" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Welcome Kenadie :)</title><link href="https://fong-lab.github.io/2025/01/13/welcome-kenadie.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Welcome Kenadie :)" /><published>2025-01-13T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-05-29T22:42:30+00:00</updated><id>https://fong-lab.github.io/2025/01/13/welcome-kenadie</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://fong-lab.github.io/2025/01/13/welcome-kenadie.html"><![CDATA[<p>Kenadie Smith has joined our lab!  Kenadie is a junior at Charles R. Drew Charter School, and a high school research scholar in the ENGAGES Program at Georgia Tech working under the mentorship of graduate student, Yichao Zhao.  She has a strong passion for mechanical engineering and design, and we’re excited to do some science together!  Welcome, Kenadie!</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Kenadie Smith has joined our lab! Kenadie is a junior at Charles R. Drew Charter School, and a high school research scholar in the ENGAGES Program at Georgia Tech working under the mentorship of graduate student, Yichao Zhao. She has a strong passion for mechanical engineering and design, and we’re excited to do some science together! Welcome, Kenadie!]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://fong-lab.github.io/images/headshots/smith.png" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://fong-lab.github.io/images/headshots/smith.png" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Welcome Ruhi :)</title><link href="https://fong-lab.github.io/2025/01/06/welcome-ruhi.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Welcome Ruhi :)" /><published>2025-01-06T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-05-29T22:42:30+00:00</updated><id>https://fong-lab.github.io/2025/01/06/welcome-ruhi</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://fong-lab.github.io/2025/01/06/welcome-ruhi.html"><![CDATA[<p>We are happy to welcome Ruhi Dua to the Fong Lab.  Ruhi is an undergraduate student majoring in Biomedical Engineering and minoring in Computing &amp; Intelligence, working with graduate student, Morgan Bade, on collection and analysis of visual neurophysiology data.  Beyond her research in the lab, Ruhi interested is the application of bioinformatics to neurological disease, drug development, and advancing healthcare practices.  Welcome, Ruhi!</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[We are happy to welcome Ruhi Dua to the Fong Lab. Ruhi is an undergraduate student majoring in Biomedical Engineering and minoring in Computing &amp; Intelligence, working with graduate student, Morgan Bade, on collection and analysis of visual neurophysiology data. Beyond her research in the lab, Ruhi interested is the application of bioinformatics to neurological disease, drug development, and advancing healthcare practices. Welcome, Ruhi!]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://fong-lab.github.io/images/headshots/dua.png" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://fong-lab.github.io/images/headshots/dua.png" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Danielle and Morgan present at SVRC</title><link href="https://fong-lab.github.io/2024/11/12/danielle-morgan-svrc.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Danielle and Morgan present at SVRC" /><published>2024-11-12T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-05-29T22:42:30+00:00</updated><id>https://fong-lab.github.io/2024/11/12/danielle-morgan-svrc</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://fong-lab.github.io/2024/11/12/danielle-morgan-svrc.html"><![CDATA[<p>Danielle and Morgan each presented posters at the Southeast Vision Research Conference in Nashville.  Danielle presented her modeling work on global and input-specific synaptic scaling, and Morgan presented her experimental work on inactivation of the retinal ON pathway.  Rob Lamprecht provided key data that laid the foundation for both studies.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Danielle and Morgan each presented posters at the Southeast Vision Research Conference in Nashville. Danielle presented her modeling work on global and input-specific synaptic scaling, and Morgan presented her experimental work on inactivation of the retinal ON pathway. Rob Lamprecht provided key data that laid the foundation for both studies.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://fong-lab.github.io/images/news/2024-danielle-svrc.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://fong-lab.github.io/images/news/2024-danielle-svrc.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Chao and Rob present at SfN</title><link href="https://fong-lab.github.io/2024/10/08/chao-rob-sfn.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Chao and Rob present at SfN" /><published>2024-10-08T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-05-29T22:42:30+00:00</updated><id>https://fong-lab.github.io/2024/10/08/chao-rob-sfn</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://fong-lab.github.io/2024/10/08/chao-rob-sfn.html"><![CDATA[<p>Chao and Rob each presented posters at the Society for Neuroscience Meeting in Chicago.  Chao showcased his research on optogenetic stimulation of the thalamus as a tool for modulating experience-dependent plasticity, while Rob highlighted his research on how selective inactivation of the retinal ON pathway can produce pathway-specific visual cortical plasticity.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Chao and Rob each presented posters at the Society for Neuroscience Meeting in Chicago. Chao showcased his research on optogenetic stimulation of the thalamus as a tool for modulating experience-dependent plasticity, while Rob highlighted his research on how selective inactivation of the retinal ON pathway can produce pathway-specific visual cortical plasticity.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://fong-lab.github.io/images/news/2024-chao-sfn.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://fong-lab.github.io/images/news/2024-chao-sfn.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Ming wins NSF CAREER Award</title><link href="https://fong-lab.github.io/2024/09/01/nsf-career-award.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Ming wins NSF CAREER Award" /><published>2024-09-01T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-05-29T22:42:30+00:00</updated><id>https://fong-lab.github.io/2024/09/01/nsf-career-award</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://fong-lab.github.io/2024/09/01/nsf-career-award.html"><![CDATA[<p>Ming has received the NSF CAREER Award in recognition of her work as a scholar-educator.  The grant will support research on rejuvenation of plasticity in the mature brain and educational outreach in the Atlanta-area blind and visually-impaired community.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Ming has received the NSF CAREER Award in recognition of her work as a scholar-educator. The grant will support research on rejuvenation of plasticity in the mature brain and educational outreach in the Atlanta-area blind and visually-impaired community.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://fong-lab.github.io/images/logos/NSF-CAREER-logo.png" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://fong-lab.github.io/images/logos/NSF-CAREER-logo.png" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Welcome Trinity :)</title><link href="https://fong-lab.github.io/2024/08/16/welcome-trinity.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Welcome Trinity :)" /><published>2024-08-16T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-05-29T22:42:30+00:00</updated><id>https://fong-lab.github.io/2024/08/16/welcome-trinity</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://fong-lab.github.io/2024/08/16/welcome-trinity.html"><![CDATA[<p>Today was Match Day at Cristo Rey Atlanta, and we are thrilled that high school senior, Trinity Calvin, matched with our group!  Trinity is an aspiring engineer and president of her school robotics club.  We’re excited for her to join our team and advances our efforts in mechanical design and community outreach. Welcome, Trinity!</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today was Match Day at Cristo Rey Atlanta, and we are thrilled that high school senior, Trinity Calvin, matched with our group! Trinity is an aspiring engineer and president of her school robotics club. We’re excited for her to join our team and advances our efforts in mechanical design and community outreach. Welcome, Trinity!]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://fong-lab.github.io/images/headshots/calvin.png" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://fong-lab.github.io/images/headshots/calvin.png" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry></feed>