<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://fong-lab.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://fong-lab.github.io/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2025-02-13T03:14:23+00:00</updated><id>https://fong-lab.github.io/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Fong Lab</title><subtitle>Harnessing plasticity for neural rehabilitation and lifelong learning</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Ming wins NSF CAREER Award</title><link href="https://fong-lab.github.io/2024/09/01/nsf-career-award.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Ming wins NSF CAREER Award" /><published>2024-09-01T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-02-13T03:11:18+00:00</updated><id>https://fong-lab.github.io/2024/09/01/nsf-career-award</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://fong-lab.github.io/2024/09/01/nsf-career-award.html"><![CDATA[<p>Ming has received the NSF CAREER Award in recognition of her work as a scholar-educator.  The grant will support research on rejuvenation of plasticity in the mature brain and educational outreach in the Atlanta-area blind and visually-impaired community.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Ming has received the NSF CAREER Award in recognition of her work as a scholar-educator. The grant will support research on rejuvenation of plasticity in the mature brain and educational outreach in the Atlanta-area blind and visually-impaired community.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://fong-lab.github.io/images/logos/NSF-CAREER-logo.png" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://fong-lab.github.io/images/logos/NSF-CAREER-logo.png" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Welcome Trinity :)</title><link href="https://fong-lab.github.io/2024/08/16/welcome-trinity.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Welcome Trinity :)" /><published>2024-08-16T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-02-13T03:11:18+00:00</updated><id>https://fong-lab.github.io/2024/08/16/welcome-trinity</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://fong-lab.github.io/2024/08/16/welcome-trinity.html"><![CDATA[<p>Today was Match Day at Cristo Rey Atlanta, and we are thrilled that high school senior, Trinity Calvin, matched with our group!  Trinity is an aspiring engineer and president of her school robotics club.  We’re excited for her to join our team and advances our efforts in mechanical design and community outreach. Welcome, Trinity!</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today was Match Day at Cristo Rey Atlanta, and we are thrilled that high school senior, Trinity Calvin, matched with our group! Trinity is an aspiring engineer and president of her school robotics club. We’re excited for her to join our team and advances our efforts in mechanical design and community outreach. Welcome, Trinity!]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://fong-lab.github.io/images/headshots/calvin.png" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://fong-lab.github.io/images/headshots/calvin.png" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Welcome Morgan :)</title><link href="https://fong-lab.github.io/2024/07/15/welcome-morgan.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Welcome Morgan :)" /><published>2024-07-15T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-02-13T03:11:18+00:00</updated><id>https://fong-lab.github.io/2024/07/15/welcome-morgan</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://fong-lab.github.io/2024/07/15/welcome-morgan.html"><![CDATA[<p>We’re excited to welcome Morgan Bade for a graduate research rotation! Morgan is an MD/PhD student at Emory, and starting her PhD training this year.  She is passionate about vision research (woot woot!) and will join us for upcoming month and a half to investigate homeostatic plasticity in the ON visual pathway.  We’re excited to see what she discovers!  Welcome, Morgan!</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[We’re excited to welcome Morgan Bade for a graduate research rotation! Morgan is an MD/PhD student at Emory, and starting her PhD training this year. She is passionate about vision research (woot woot!) and will join us for upcoming month and a half to investigate homeostatic plasticity in the ON visual pathway. We’re excited to see what she discovers! Welcome, Morgan!]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://fong-lab.github.io/images/headshots/bade.png" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://fong-lab.github.io/images/headshots/bade.png" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Welcome Peyton :)</title><link href="https://fong-lab.github.io/2024/06/17/welcome-peyton.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Welcome Peyton :)" /><published>2024-06-17T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-02-13T03:11:18+00:00</updated><id>https://fong-lab.github.io/2024/06/17/welcome-peyton</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://fong-lab.github.io/2024/06/17/welcome-peyton.html"><![CDATA[<p>Peyton-Zoe Jackson has joined our lab as a high school research scholar via the ENGAGES Program at Georgia Tech.  Peyton is a rising senior at Benjamin E. Mays High School with an interest in medicine and engineering.  She will be working with her graduate mentor, Yichao Zhao, to develop optogenetic approaches for driving thalamocortical plasticity.  Welcome, Peyton!</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Peyton-Zoe Jackson has joined our lab as a high school research scholar via the ENGAGES Program at Georgia Tech. Peyton is a rising senior at Benjamin E. Mays High School with an interest in medicine and engineering. She will be working with her graduate mentor, Yichao Zhao, to develop optogenetic approaches for driving thalamocortical plasticity. Welcome, Peyton!]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://fong-lab.github.io/images/headshots/jackson.png" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://fong-lab.github.io/images/headshots/jackson.png" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Goalball tournament</title><link href="https://fong-lab.github.io/2024/05/24/goalball.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Goalball tournament" /><published>2024-05-24T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-02-13T03:11:18+00:00</updated><id>https://fong-lab.github.io/2024/05/24/goalball</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://fong-lab.github.io/2024/05/24/goalball.html"><![CDATA[<p>We love goalball!  The lab returned for a second year to volunteer at the Southeast Regional National Qualifier goalball tournament.  Danielle, Rob, Chao, Nahreen, and Ming helped set up the nets and tape lines and serve as judges/scorekeepers.  We reconnected with friends from last year and met some new ones.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[We love goalball! The lab returned for a second year to volunteer at the Southeast Regional National Qualifier goalball tournament. Danielle, Rob, Chao, Nahreen, and Ming helped set up the nets and tape lines and serve as judges/scorekeepers. We reconnected with friends from last year and met some new ones.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://fong-lab.github.io/images/news/2024-goalball.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://fong-lab.github.io/images/news/2024-goalball.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Chao awarded Wells Fellowship</title><link href="https://fong-lab.github.io/2024/05/20/chao-wells-fellowship.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Chao awarded Wells Fellowship" /><published>2024-05-20T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-02-13T03:11:18+00:00</updated><id>https://fong-lab.github.io/2024/05/20/chao-wells-fellowship</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://fong-lab.github.io/2024/05/20/chao-wells-fellowship.html"><![CDATA[<p>Hooray!  Yichao Zhao has received the J. Norman &amp; Rosalyn Wells Fellowship.  The award will support his work on developing an optogenetic stimulation system for driving plasticity in the mature mouse brain.  Congratulations, Chao!</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Hooray! Yichao Zhao has received the J. Norman &amp; Rosalyn Wells Fellowship. The award will support his work on developing an optogenetic stimulation system for driving plasticity in the mature mouse brain. Congratulations, Chao!]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://fong-lab.github.io/images/headshots/zhao.png" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://fong-lab.github.io/images/headshots/zhao.png" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Robotics workshop for visually-impaired youth</title><link href="https://fong-lab.github.io/2024/04/13/solar-car-workshop.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Robotics workshop for visually-impaired youth" /><published>2024-04-13T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-02-13T03:11:18+00:00</updated><id>https://fong-lab.github.io/2024/04/13/solar-car-workshop</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://fong-lab.github.io/2024/04/13/solar-car-workshop.html"><![CDATA[<p>The Fong lab organized a robotics workshop for blind and visually-impaired youth to build, modify, and race solar cars!  The idea was the brainchild of high school student, Nahreen Shamon Ayala.  Nahreen, Chao, Rob, Rohan, and Ming all participated as mentors.  The workshop took place at Clough Commons and was sponsored by the GT-Emory Department of Biomedical Engineering, the GT Center for Education Integrating Science, Mathematics, and Computing, and the Atlanta Center for Visually Impaired.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Fong lab organized a robotics workshop for blind and visually-impaired youth to build, modify, and race solar cars! The idea was the brainchild of high school student, Nahreen Shamon Ayala. Nahreen, Chao, Rob, Rohan, and Ming all participated as mentors. The workshop took place at Clough Commons and was sponsored by the GT-Emory Department of Biomedical Engineering, the GT Center for Education Integrating Science, Mathematics, and Computing, and the Atlanta Center for Visually Impaired.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://fong-lab.github.io/images/news/2024-solar-car-workshop.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://fong-lab.github.io/images/news/2024-solar-car-workshop.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Welcome Adam :)</title><link href="https://fong-lab.github.io/2024/03/04/welcome-adam.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Welcome Adam :)" /><published>2024-03-04T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-02-13T03:11:18+00:00</updated><id>https://fong-lab.github.io/2024/03/04/welcome-adam</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://fong-lab.github.io/2024/03/04/welcome-adam.html"><![CDATA[<p>We’re excited to welcome Adam Kotar to the lab as a new research technician.  Adam joins the lab with an MS in Biomedical Engineering from University of Alabama at Birmingham and a BS in Civil Engineering from the University of South Alabama.  He has worked in breast cancer research in recent years, but we’ve successfully wooed him to join our efforts on neural plasticity.  Welcome, Adam!</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[We’re excited to welcome Adam Kotar to the lab as a new research technician. Adam joins the lab with an MS in Biomedical Engineering from University of Alabama at Birmingham and a BS in Civil Engineering from the University of South Alabama. He has worked in breast cancer research in recent years, but we’ve successfully wooed him to join our efforts on neural plasticity. Welcome, Adam!]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://fong-lab.github.io/images/headshots/kotar.png" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://fong-lab.github.io/images/headshots/kotar.png" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Nahreen admitted early to Georgia Tech</title><link href="https://fong-lab.github.io/2023/12/08/nahreen-GT-admission.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Nahreen admitted early to Georgia Tech" /><published>2023-12-08T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-02-13T03:11:18+00:00</updated><id>https://fong-lab.github.io/2023/12/08/nahreen-GT-admission</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://fong-lab.github.io/2023/12/08/nahreen-GT-admission.html"><![CDATA[<p>Nahreen was admitted early action to Georgia Tech!  <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=De6dJfyDBks">Dean Beyah was at her high school</a> to personally deliver her letter of admission.  Congrats, Nahreen (and also, please come to GT)!</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Nahreen was admitted early action to Georgia Tech! Dean Beyah was at her high school to personally deliver her letter of admission. Congrats, Nahreen (and also, please come to GT)!]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://fong-lab.github.io/images/news/2023-nahreen-admission.png" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://fong-lab.github.io/images/news/2023-nahreen-admission.png" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Rob and Chao present at SfN</title><link href="https://fong-lab.github.io/2023/11/14/rob-presents-sfn.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Rob and Chao present at SfN" /><published>2023-11-14T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-02-13T03:11:18+00:00</updated><id>https://fong-lab.github.io/2023/11/14/rob-presents-sfn</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://fong-lab.github.io/2023/11/14/rob-presents-sfn.html"><![CDATA[<p>Rob and Chao present a poster at the Society for Neuroscience Meeting in Washington, DC.  It is the first abstract from our lab!</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Rob and Chao present a poster at the Society for Neuroscience Meeting in Washington, DC. It is the first abstract from our lab!]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://fong-lab.github.io/images/news/2023-rob-sfn.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://fong-lab.github.io/images/news/2023-rob-sfn.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry></feed>